Yawning is something we all do – maybe because we’re bored carrying out tedious tasks or because we’re tired.
打哈欠是我们每个人都会做的事——可能是因为我们在做单调乏味的任务时感到无聊，也可能是因为疲惫。
Sometimes, just seeing other people yawn can set you off.
有时候，仅仅看到别人打哈欠你也会跟着打。
But is this biological function really contagious, and why do we do it in the first place?
但这种生理功能真的会传染吗？首先，我们为什么会打哈欠呢？
Many of us think we open our mouths when we yawn to take in more oxygen, but in fact it appears there is no clear biological reason.
我们很多人认为，打哈欠时张大嘴巴是为了吸入更多氧气，但实际上，这似乎并没有明确的生物学原因。
According to BBC Bitesize, new research suggests it might be because yawning cools the brain down and prevents it from overheating, much like the fan in your laptop.
据BBC学习频道（BBC Bitesize）报道，新的研究表明，打哈欠可能是为了给大脑降温，防止其过热，就像你笔记本电脑里的风扇一样。
This might be why we’re more likely to feel drowsy and yawn in warm temperatures.
这或许就是为什么我们在温暖的环境中更容易感到昏昏欲睡并打哈欠的原因。
What is clear is that we yawn more when we’re exhausted and ready for a nap, and we can’t control when we do it – once we start, there’s no stopping us!
可以确定的是，当我们疲惫不堪、准备小睡时，会更频繁地打哈欠，而且我们无法控制打哈欠的时机——一旦开始，就停不下来！
But it’s also true that yawning is a very contagious behaviour.
但打哈欠确实是一种极具传染性的行为。
John Drury, a researcher from Sussex University, told the BBC that “it’s meant to be automatic; it’s something that you can’t stop.
萨塞克斯大学的研究员约翰·德鲁里向BBC表示：“它本来就是无意识的，是你无法阻止的事情。
Dogs yawn when their owners yawn, animals yawn to each other.
主人打哈欠时，狗也会跟着打，动物之间也会相互打哈欠。
It happens whether you want to or not.”
不管你愿不愿意，它都会发生。”
His research into this cognitive behaviour found that there is a connection with our social group and how close we are to the people in it.
他对这种认知行为的研究发现，这与我们的社交圈以及我们和圈内人的亲密程度有关。
If we identify with the person who exhibits the behaviour, we are likely to copy it too.
如果我们认同表现出这种行为的人，就很可能会模仿他们。
Other research by the University of Nottingham in 2017 found similar results.
诺丁汉大学2017年的另一项研究也得出了类似的结果。
They asked volunteers to watch other people yawn. They found their ability to resist yawning when others around them yawned was limited.
研究人员让志愿者观看别人打哈欠的画面，发现他们在周围人打哈欠时，抗拒打哈欠的能力很有限。
And the urge to yawn was increased when people were told they couldn’t.
而且当被告知不能打哈欠时，打哈欠的欲望反而会增强。
They also found, when using electrical stimulation, that they were able to increase people’s desire to yawn.
他们还发现，通过电流刺激，能够增强人们打哈欠的欲望。
These findings, they say, could be useful because it could help treat other conditions like Tourette’s, which involve the same area of the brain.
研究人员表示，这些发现可能很有价值，因为它有助于治疗图雷特综合征等其他疾病——这些疾病涉及与打哈欠有关的大脑的同一区域。
What is certain is that a yawn can creep up on us at any time even when we think we’re not tired – but, I hope, not when you’re reading this article!
可以肯定的是，即使我们认为自己不累，打哈欠的冲动也可能在任何时候不知不觉袭来——不过，我希望你在读这篇文章的时候不会这样！